Curriculum Vitae

Mr. Love Mavar (MBA - HR) Mobile: +91 9978829990

Mail ID: love.mavar@gmail.com

Skype: mavar.hr

Linked In: http://in.linkedin.com/pub/love-mavar/51/646/a43/



Location Preference: Anywhere in India and Abroad.

Personal Summary

A forward thinking, hardworking and dynamic Manager who will ensure that what has to be done is done effectively and efficiently within the constraints of budget and time. He is the type of person who gets a kick out of going above and beyond the call of duty and has the proven leadership skills along with the necessary tenacity needed to get the most demanding of jobs done. He is a negotiator who can successfully talk through senior candidates and recruit them in HR Budget. Right now he is looking for an opportunity to build a career with a company that has a friendly, flexible working environment where he can develop and thrive.

Seeking position at Senior Level for Human Resources with an organisation of high repute

Career Summary

MBA in HR with 11+ years of exposure in Real Estate, Construction, Hospitality, Pharmaceutical, Retail, Insurance & Information Technology.

Currently working at UNIQUE Group (Real Estate, Hospitality, Insurance, Pharma) Ahmedabad since December 2018 to till date as **Group HR Head.**

Previously worked with PMS Group (Infrastructure, Construction, Rental Construction Equipment, Scaffolding, Piling, Ready Mix Concrete & IT) Ahmedabad since April 2017 to August 2018 as **Sr. Manager HR & admin.**

I have worked with Shree Balaji Group (Real Estate, Hospitality & Retail) Ahmedabad since December 2014 to March 2017 as **Group HR Head.**

I have worked with NITI Group (IT Distribution, Pharma & Hospitality) since August 2012 to August 2014 as **Group HR Manager** – Africa (Kenya, Uganda, Rwanda, Burundi, Tanzania, Nigeria, Ghana, Ethiopia, and South Sudan) Mauritius & Dubai.

I have worked with StemCyte India Therapeutics Pvt. Ltd- Pharma Ahmedabad since May 2011 to August 2012 as **HR Manager** (PAN INDIA).

I have worked with Pravasi Construction Ahmedabad Since June 2008 to April 2011 as ${\bf HR}$ Manager.

I have worked with CITIBANK N.A Ahmedabad since April 2007 to May 2008 as an Executive in Corporate Banking – Trade Department.

Career History

UNIQUE Group (Real Estate, Hospitality, Insurance, Pharma) Ahmedabad – Gujarat. From December 2018 till date Group HR Head.

Total Employee Strength: 800+ Taking Reporting: HR 5 People Reporting to: Managing Director

PMS Group (Infrastructure, Construction, Rental Construction Equipment, Scaffolding, Piling, Ready Mix Concrete & IT) Ahmedabad – Gujarat.

From April 2017 till August 2018 Sr. Manager HR & Admin

Total Employee Strength: 500+

Taking Reporting: HR 3 People & Site Incharge - 20

Reporting to: Managing Director

Premium Clients















Shree Balaji Group (Construction, Retail & Hospitality) Ahmedabad - Gujarat.

From Dec 2014 to March 2017 Group HR Head

Total Employee Strength: 600 Taking Reporting: HR 4 People Reporting to: Managing Director

NITI Group (IT, Pharmaceutical & Hospitality) Africa & Middle East

From Aug 2012 to Aug 2014 Group HR Manager

Job posting: Kenya & Dubai

Total Employee Strength: 600

Taking Reporting: HR 2 People & Country Manager -10

Reporting to: CEO

Stemcyte India Therapeutics Pvt Ltd - Ahmedabad (Gujarat)

From May 2011 to Aug 2012 HR Manager - PAN India

Total Employee Strength: 500

Taking Reporting: HR 3 People & Branch Manager -15

Reporting to: Chief Operating Officer (COO)

Pravasi Construction - Ahmedabad (Gujarat)

From June 2008 to April 2011 HR Manager

Total Employee Strength: 300

Taking Reporting: HR 2 People & Site Incharge - 8

Reporting to: Managing Director

Citi Bank - Ahmedabad (Gujarat)

From April 2007 to May 2008

Executive

Total Employee Strength: 2500

Reporting to: Manager

The overall management and development of all HR aspects for the company, including:

Domestic Work Experience

Job Description:

Recruitment:

- Plan manning budget and handle recruitment needs across levels
- > Design job descriptions and KRA as per organization requirements
- > Handle entire scope of recruitment with use of Job Portals (Naukri, Monster, Indeed)
 Professional Network LinkedIn, Placement consultancy, Advertisement in Newspaper
- > Referral checks, negotiations & offer settlements
- Co-ordinate & conduct campus interviews at engineering colleges & leading B schools

Employee Life Cycle:

- Handle On boarding & Induction
- > Maintain & update employee database
- Manage daily HR operations in employee life cycle
- > Plan manpower allocation and budget as per functional requirements
- Introduced on line HRIS system on share point for handling Attendance / Leave management and HR records.
- > Maintain affable approach & connecting link between management & employees
- Prepare various HR dashboard reports & data summary for management review and assessment
- Prepare compensation benefits structure & manage payroll requirements

HR Processes:

- Design, Develop & Implement HR Policies and SOP
- Prepare Organization Chart
- Review polices and amendments as per rules & regulations / statutory norms
- Monitor policy adherence across the organization

Statutory Compliance:

- Provide data for completing statutory compliances.
- > Taking care of below Labor Laws In India.

LAWS RELATING TO SOCIAL SECURITY IN INDIA

Employees Provident Funds and Miscellaneous Provisions Act, 1952 Employees' State Insurance Act, 1948

LAWS RELATING TO WAGES IN INDIA

Minimum Wages Act, 1948 Payment of Wages Act, 1936 Payment of Bonus Act, 1965

LAWS RELATING TO WORKING HOURS, CONDITIONS OF SERVICE AND EMPLOYMENT

Factories Act, 1948

Shops and Commercial Establishments Act

Contract Labour (Regulation & Abolition) Act, 1970

The Workmen Compensation Act, 1923

LABOUR WELFARE ACT

Payment of Gratuity Act, 1972

- > Address compliance issues and concerns
- > Update records as per Govt. Amendments
- Arrange processes for Audits and Inspections

Resource Planning & Attrition Management:

- > Allocate resources as per project needs
- Map Manning Tracker and update as per organizational requirements
- > Identify & fill gaps in attrition analysis
- Use effective communication channels & approach to handle attrition

Performance Management System:

- > Conduct annual performance evaluations & review
- Collect data and analyze to derive review ratings
- Finalize the individual appraisal score
- > Implement calculations for processing revised salaries
- > Handle probation reviews & confirmations

General Administration:

Oversee all administration requirements of the work place

Employee Engagement & Welfare Programs:

- Plan annual budget & calendar for employee welfare
- Initiate team building activities and ice breaking events
- Arrange picnics and team gatherings
- Plan & organize annual event
- Employee Group Life Insurance Policy.

Training & Development:

- > Identify training needs and arrange knowledge transfer
- > Arrange & enroll for Webinars & Seminars
- > Coach & counsel employees for communication & inter personal skills

Organization Development:

- Prepare & update organizational mapping as per needs
- Make periodic amendments based on change management
- ➤ Implement changes as per organization structuring & expansion

Overseas Work Experience

Group HR Manager

From Aug 2012 to Aug 2014

NITI Group (IT, Pharmaceutical & Hospitality) Africa & Middle East

I was handling Africa (Kenya, Uganda, Rwanda, Burundi, Tanzania, Nigeria, Ghana, Ethiopia, and South Sudan) Mauritius & Dubai as Group HR Manager.

Job Role & Responsibilities:

- ✓ Ensure and coordinate recruitment processes within TAT.
- ✓ Prepare offer letters to be signed by the VP HR and follow up for all documents before formal appointment letter is handed over.
- ✓ Prepare appointment letters.
- √ Maintenance of employee database Master data. (HRIS Software)
- ✓ Employment confirmation and transfers.
- ✓ Arrange for induction program and welcome aboard mails.
- √ Maintenance of joining docket and individual files for all employees.
- √ Handle salary computation / tour claims / loan applications processing etc.
- √ Handle NSSF/NHIF/PAYE (Statutory Africa)
- √ Handle WPS (Statutory of Middle East UAE)
- √ Follow up on employee visas, work permit.
- √ Receive grievance & dismissal reports from countries.
- ✓ Responsible for the maintenance and upkeep of department files and registers and employee attendance.
- ✓ Employee Exits.
- ✓ Maintenance of Leave records.
- √ Full and Final settlements.
- ✓ Maintain various HR metrics like attrition/discipline etc.
- √ Ensure KRA and performance appraisal system is being adhered too.
- ✓ Other day-to-day HR Administrative activities.
- ✓ Employee motivational activities within set budgets.
- ✓ Co-ordinate all training programs at company and Dept level and escalate any nonconformity to VP - HR.
- ✓ Ensure process adherence within team.
- √ Other activities given time to time.
- √HR Audit.
- ✓ Reporting To CEO

Professional Education

- MBA From Institute of Business Management & Research, B-School with 65.78% First Class March 2010
- > Graduation in **Bachelors of Commerce** From Gujarat University, H.L. College of Commerce with 58% Marks (March-2006)
- GNIIT (3 years Diploma in Software Engineering) From NIIT with Distinction (74%)
- Class XII from GHSEB with 73.50% Marks (March April 2003)
- Class X from GSEB with 70.29% Marks (April May 2001

Professional Qualifications

Operating Systems: Windows 2000 Server, Windows XP, Windows 7 & Vista.

RDBMS: Microsoft SQL Server 2000 and 2005

Programming Languages: Core Java, J2EE, HTML, VB.Net and ASP.Net Strength in Application: VB.Net and Microsoft SQL Server 2000 and 2005

Accounting Tools: MS Office, Tally

Personal Details

Date of Birth: 16th Feb 1986

Languages Known: English, Hindi & Gujarati **Alternate Mail:** love_mavar@yahoo.co.in

Alternate Mobile: 09925922790

Present Address: C-106, Umed Park Society, Opp. Kala Sagar Mall, Ahmedabad –Gujarat (India)

References: Available on request